<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Reference on Presidium</title><link>/reference/</link><description>Recent content in Reference on Presidium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>SPAN Digital</copyright><atom:link href="/reference/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Configuration</title><link>/reference/configuration/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/reference/configuration/</guid><description>This is a sample Presidium configuration file:
languageCode: en-us title: &amp;#34;Sample Title&amp;#34; copyright: Template Footer pluralizelisttitles: false markup: goldmark: renderer: Unsafe: true parser: attribute: block: true highlight: style: github menu: Main: - identifier: organization-overview name: Organization Overview url: / weight: 1 - identifier: solution-overview name: Solution Overview url: /solution-overview/ weight: 2 - identifier: technology-stack name: Technology Stack url: /technology-stack/ weight: 3 - identifier: tool-chain name: Tool Chain url: /tool-chain/ weight: 4 - identifier: dev-environment-setup name: Dev Environment Setup url: /dev-environment-setup/ weight: 5 - identifier: getting-started name: Getting Started url: /getting-started/ weight: 6 - identifier: reference name: Reference url: /reference/ weight: 7 - identifier: updates name: Updates url: /updates/ weight: 8 outputFormats: MenuIndex: baseName: menu mediaType: application/json SearchMap: baseName: searchmap mediaType: application/json outputs: home: - HTML - RSS - MenuIndex - SearchMap module: imports: - path: github.</description></item><item><title>Themes</title><link>/reference/themes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/reference/themes/</guid><description>Presidium provides some themes when spinning up your Presidium Site through the command line. You will see something like this when running presidium init:
Select a theme ✔ Presidium Theme - (Presidium&amp;#39;s default theme) If you already have a presidium site, you can enable your theme by adding a module in the configuration file:
module: imports: - path: &amp;lt;Your theme&amp;gt; Logo The default Presidium logo image is placed and loaded from the pre-configured template.</description></item><item><title>Directories</title><link>/reference/directories/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/reference/directories/</guid><description>Articles are stored in the content directory. Associated resources, such as images, are stored in the media directory. The config.yaml file is used to configure the project.
Directory Description ./config.yaml General options to configure the project ./content Articles ./static Various resources for the project (images, imported content, etc.) All content changes are monitored; any change triggers a regeneration of the site.</description></item><item><title>Images</title><link>/reference/images/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/reference/images/</guid><description>Images Images used within the content should be placed in a static/images directory
/static/images/ -- static/doc-workflow.png Logos and favicons Logos The Logo of the site appears above the Menu Navigation.
Logos should be placed in the static/images directory.
Note: If a brand module is used the instruction above does not apply. Ensure the brand module includes the static/images directory with the logo inside.
The menu bar Logo can be configured in the config file, under params:</description></item></channel></rss>