<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Updates on Presidium</title><link>/updates/</link><description>Recent content in Updates on Presidium</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>SPAN Digital</copyright><atom:link href="/updates/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>v2.0.0</title><link>/updates/v2.0.0/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/updates/v2.0.0/</guid><description>26 May 2022
Summary Replaced Jekyll with Hugo as our static site generator.
New Features Presidium CLI tool that allows you to scaffold new sites from a template. A new Presidium Hugo Theme that replaces the default Jekyll theme.</description></item><item><title>v0.1.42</title><link>/updates/v0.1.42/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/updates/v0.1.42/</guid><description>21 November 2018
Summary General improvement that includes a small bug fix to the gh-pages command.
Bug Fixes/Enhancements 174</description></item><item><title>v0.1.41</title><link>/updates/v0.1.41/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/updates/v0.1.41/</guid><description>20 November 2018
Summary General improvements that include updates to the linking out of external sites.
New Features Sections that are External URLs have the option of linking out in a new or existing tab. Site Config If you intend to use this release, make sure your site config is up to date with the latest config.
Bug Fixes/Enhancements 172</description></item><item><title>v0.1.39</title><link>/updates/v0.1.39/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/updates/v0.1.39/</guid><description>19 September 2018
Summary General improvements that include a new feature to allow sections to be external URLs.
New Features Sections can now be External URLs Site Config If you intend to use this release, make sure your site config is up to date with the latest config.
Bug Fixes/Enhancements 172</description></item><item><title>v0.1.38</title><link>/updates/v0.1.38/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/updates/v0.1.38/</guid><description>19 September 2018
Summary General improvements that include updates to the scope feature and new documentation content.
New Features Articles can now have multiple Scopes Corrections to the usage of Statuses in the site config Site Config If you intend to use this release, make sure your site config is up to date with the latest config.
Bug Fixes/Enhancements https://github.com/SPANDigital/presidium/issues/170 https://github.com/SPANDigital/presidium/issues/169</description></item><item><title>v0.1.37</title><link>/updates/v0.1.37/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/updates/v0.1.37/</guid><description>14 September 2018
Summary General improvements that include small bug fixes to Presidium and new documentation content.
New Features Introduced the ability to build internal and external facing documentation using scopes Optional cname parameter in the site config Site Config If you intend to use this release, make sure your site config is up to date with the latest config.
Bug Fixes/Enhancements Github Issues</description></item><item><title>v0.1.9</title><link>/updates/v0.1.9/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/updates/v0.1.9/</guid><description>4 July 2017
Summary General improvements that include small bug fixes to Presidium and new documentation content.
New Content Markdown New Features Tooltips Landing Page presidium-swagger - A Java-based tool built on top of Swagger2Markup that imports your API&amp;rsquo;s Swagger into your documentation. Site Config If you intend to use this release, make sure your site config is up to date with the latest config.
Bug Fixes 39 50</description></item><item><title>v0.1.8</title><link>/updates/v0.1.8/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/updates/v0.1.8/</guid><description>20 June 2017
Summary General improvements include small bug fixes to Presidium and new documentation content.
Site Config If you intend to use this release, make sure your site config is up to date with the latest config.
New Content Features Benefits Plan Content Development Design Documentation Structure Define Learning Objectives Inventory Existing Content Use Article Templates Writing Effective Articles Bug Fixes #44 #43</description></item><item><title>v0.1.7</title><link>/updates/v0.1.7/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/updates/v0.1.7/</guid><description>13 June 2017
Summary General improvements and features that include support for Jsdoc ingestion and minor bug fixes.
New Features Jsdoc Import: A node tool that imports Javascript comments into your documentation. Bug Fixes #5</description></item><item><title>v0.1.6</title><link>/updates/v0.1.6/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/updates/v0.1.6/</guid><description>6 June 2017
Summary General improvements and features that include support for semantic versioning, Javadoc ingestion, and link validation.
New Features Semantic Versioning: Adds support to publish and switch between different site versions Javadoc Import: Java doclet to import source code comments to Presidium Link validation: Tool to check for any broken links</description></item><item><title>License</title><link>/updates/license/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/updates/license/</guid><description>Presidium was created by SPAN Digital
Copyright 2022 SPAN Digital Licensed under the Apache License, Version 2.0 (the &amp;#34;License&amp;#34;); you may not use this file except in compliance with the License. You may obtain a copy of the License at [http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0] Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software distributed under the License is distributed on an &amp;#34;AS IS&amp;#34; BASIS, WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied.</description></item></channel></rss>