<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Key Concepts on Presidium</title>
    <link>/key-concepts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Key Concepts on Presidium</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>SPAN Digital</copyright><atom:link href="/key-concepts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Presidium&#39;s Learning Model</title>
      <link>/key-concepts/presidium-learning-model/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/key-concepts/presidium-learning-model/</guid>
      <description>Presidium is more than a framework for producing documentation. It asks you to think about, structure, author, and publish content based on sensible best practices so you can write effective documentation, rather than producing documentation for documentation’s sake.
Supporting Learning Objectives &amp;amp; Efficiency Presidium recommends creating small micro-articles that convey enough information to fulfill a learning objective. Small articles are advantageous because they:
 Usually only require a single author Force the author to focus on effectively describing a single concept Enable authors to quickly add documentation while also working on a product or service.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Menu Structure</title>
      <link>/key-concepts/menu-structure/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/key-concepts/menu-structure/</guid>
      <description>Structure For simplicity and transparency, the menu structure and associated directory structure are the same.
Behavior A significant feature of the menu is its tree structure: each section or subsection is a node and content traverses from each node through its children. In Presidium, the node name or title becomes the main header of the page. Everything outside of that sub-tree is not presented on the page. In this example, the user has clicked Content Structure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Templates</title>
      <link>/key-concepts/templates/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/key-concepts/templates/</guid>
      <description>Presidium includes article templates for each of the pre-defined sections. Templates are text documents that contain instructions and Markdown which can be modified to meet your needs.
Templates encourage consistency and provide a simple checklist that an author can use for inspiration.
 Default Template Design Template Onboarding Template  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Authoring Workflow</title>
      <link>/key-concepts/authoring/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/key-concepts/authoring/</guid>
      <description>The following workflow is recommended for authoring content using Presidium.
Identify the Author Whether you’re creating a single article or an entire section, make sure to include the author tag in the front matter.
Work Locally Presidium encourages you to write and review documentation on your local machine, rather than making changes directly on Github. The advantages to this workflow are:
 Changes are immediately viewable You can leverage Presidium’s validation tools Git commit history will have less noise  Protect Master If you own the documentation project, make sure you prevent others from making commits or pushing to the Master branch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning Objectives</title>
      <link>/key-concepts/learning-objectives/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/key-concepts/learning-objectives/</guid>
      <description>You should define the knowledge and skill set of your target audience before starting your documentation. You can then use this information to avoid wasting time explaining information your audience already knows.
Just as stories are used to define software, learning objectives can be written using a standard template: As a [user] of the [solution] I [know a specific piece of information] or can [perform a specific task]
For each learning objective, you should:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Markdown</title>
      <link>/key-concepts/markdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/key-concepts/markdown/</guid>
      <description>Markdown is an ubiquitous, lighweight markup language known to almost any engineer. If you don’t know Markdown, it’s easy to learn. Presidium uses a version of Markdown known as Github Flavoured Markdown and leverages this ‘common tongue’ to enable multiple contributors to create documentation quickly without wasting time doing point &amp;amp; click styling or having to alter HTML and CSS.
Style Guides For any documentation project, a Markdown style guide ensures that contributors write documentation that is consistent with your intended tone and layout.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Micro-articles</title>
      <link>/key-concepts/micro-articles/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/key-concepts/micro-articles/</guid>
      <description>Presidium is built on sound theoretical strategies for developing learning content and managing knowledge assets. The core of this approach is the development of specific focused micro-articles that explain individual concepts.
This splits the problem of content development into two parts:
  Defining a site outline based on the concepts that must be documented and how they should be sequenced and presented.
  Developing articles that each explain each concept, using a standard template to ensure consistency.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Content Maintenance</title>
      <link>/key-concepts/content-maintenance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/key-concepts/content-maintenance/</guid>
      <description>Presidium is designed to make it easy to write and maintain your documentation. Instead of a monolithic document, Presidium manages a directory structure of micro-articles. The directory structure maps to the sections of your site, while the articles are joined together to build the content of each section. You can create a directory to add new sections and sub-sections. Each section contains a sample article template you can use as a starting point when creating new content.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
